

Fabion (Fabian) Abazaj

A graduate economist, with a 5+ year experience on finance/accounting, a 4+ year experience in sales and customer service and a career aspiration on the data science and programming track. Very enthusiastic about energy and the environment, data analysis, machine learning and the new cognitive era, but also communication with people and interaction with different cultures. With international and multidisciplinary background, a strong learning attitude, broadmindedness and diverse interests. Very passionate about animal protection and the empowering of diverse social groups.

🔀 fabio.ab94@gmail.com

Warsaw, Poland

linkedin.com/in/fabianabazaj

+48 503 516427

iii 10 January, 1994

instagram.com/fabian.aj

WORK EXPERIENCE

09.2020 - Present

Accountant

Mi Casa Tu Casa AS Bergen, Norway

(0)

- Accounts Payable: creation of tracker for regular and incidental suppliers and the invoiced amounts; registering of invoices and receipts from supplies; payments-2-bank; reconciliation of deposit return obligations after end of rental agreements
- Accounts Receivable: invoices to after CS & Operations dept requests for short-term services; FUP on unpaid invoices & debt collection; reports from Booking.com/Stripe/Airbnb/Vipps and other CRM systems
- <u>Journal Entries & General Ledger</u>: registering of assets and other accounting events by the rules of Norske Regnskapsstandarder; setting of automatic depreciations, accruals and deferrals, other entries
- Banking & Loans: bank reconciliations for 4 different companies of the group and 12 different accounts in total; registration of monthly loan installment and interest transactions
- Budgeting & Root-Cause Analysis: building of budget and expense/revenue forecast; analysis of budget/forecast vs actuals; root-cause analysis on profit/loss; cashflow statement
- <u>Payroll, Tax & Subsidies:</u> payroll tracker creation for hourly wage employees; payroll form preparation, checks for VAT submission every bi-monthly period; applications for COVID-19 relief packages
- <u>Services pricing:</u> pricing of hotels and properties short-term and long-term rentals according to market research, narrow competitors and market benchmarks

07.2017 - 08.2020

Financial Analyst (Nordic Market)

IBM Sofia, Bulgaria

- Contract management: review and registration of new deals (e.g. client history, credit rating and billing history, minimum revenue commitment, historical revenue); signings & revenue backlog weekly/monthly/quarterly certification for commercial contracts; assistance w/ billing; revenue reconciliation & compliance between reporting systems; monitoring of A/R, DSO and provisions; execution of contractual obligations, penalties & other charges; contract (re)negotiation support; SO/PO management; journal entries in ledger (e.g. clearing of cost centers & unallocated costs, reclassification/correction entries, accruals & deferrals)
- Reporting & advisory: results reporting to Account Executives, Sales, CFOs; forecast & roadmap building w/ opportunities and risks, by streams of revenue and nature of costs; source of revenue & erosion analysis; variance analysis; gap analysis of BC/FC vs actuals; labor rates calculation; bundling of expendable assets for capitalization; maintenance & installation labor capitalization; communications with Accounting, Audit, Customer Fulfillment, Procurement and Suppliers; consulting on sales opportunities;
- <u>Projects:</u> Booked-to-Billed (SOX compliance) process harmonization across Europe; Billing/Forecasting/ Intercompany Agreement process metrics; Contract loading process optimization; "Be Equal Ambassador"- Diversity & Inclusion Ambassador

Contact: Daniela Lefterova – <u>daniela.lefterova@ibm.com</u>

12.2016 - 06.2017

Business Development Trainee

Stavros Niarchos Foundation Cultural Center Kallithea, Greece

<u>Business Development:</u> Member/visitor insights; market research & competition analysis; ROI reporting; member database administration (CRM); inventory management; visitors' experience; good practices; event planning/management; bookings; guided tour scripts translation

Contact: Christina Coveou - <u>c.coveou@snfcc.org</u>

02.2016 - 05.2016

Research Assistant Economist

Institute of International Economic Relations Athens, Greece

Research on the Albania-Greece bilateral relations (2009-2016): EEZ agreement; Greek FDIs; the Greek crisis impact on the Albanian market; nationalism & its impact on economic relations; perspective of problem resolutions within the accession framework of Albania in the EU; dissemination; conferences invitations; comms with embassies/institutions representatives

Contact: Stella Milioti - <u>stellam@sae-epe.gr</u>

11.2015 - 02.2016

Consulting Intern

PROMEA Neo Pyschiko, Greece

- <u>Consulting research:</u> research tasks for EU-funded project activities, learning material translations (EN→FR), research for new contacts, dissemination, data entry in Salesforce
- <u>Finance:</u> monitoring of monthly expenditure; expense forecasts; month-end closing assistance; reporting & cash flow forecasting; contracts & subcontracts payments monitoring

Contact: Yiannis Pappas - info@promea.gr

EDUCATION

)8.2020 - Present (06.2022) **NORWEGIAN SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS,** Norway, M.Sc. in Economics & Business Administration Major in Energy, Natural Resources and the Environment

Topics: Electricity Markets, Natural Resource Industries, Renewables, Shipping, Sustainable Energy, Petroleum Economics, Sustainable Finance & Marketing etc

Minor in Business Analytics

Topics: R Programming, Python Programming, Forecasting, Predictive Analytics, Insurance Analytics Energy Industry Analytics, Big Data Applications etc

WARSAW SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS, Poland (10.2021 – 02.2022)

Erasmus+ Student Exchange, 4.75/5 (Top 10%)

Topics: International Leadership, International Energy Conflicts & Cooperation, Sustainable Energy, R & Python Programming, Managerial Accounting, FinTech, M&As

10.2012 - 02.2016

ATHENS UNIVERSITY OF ECONOMICS & BUSINESS, Greece, "Ptychion" (B.Sc.) in Economics Economic Policy & Theory Group Orientation

8.89/10 (Excellent - Top 8.57%)

UNIVERSITY OF COLOGNE, Germany (10.2014 – 03.2015)
 Erasmus+ Student Exchange, 1.9/1 (Very Good - Top 10%)

09.2009 - 06.2012

3RD GENERAL HIGH SCHOOL "MILTOS KOUNTOURAS", Greece

<u>Classical Studies</u> Group Orientation (Ancient Greek, History, Latin, Literature) 19.6/20 (Excellent – top 3%)

LANGUAGES

Native Proficiency

- Albanian
- Greek

Fluent working proficiency

- English C2 Level (ECPE)
- Spanish C1 Level (DELE)

Competent working proficiency

- Italian B2 Level
- Norwegian B2 level

CERTIFICATES

Coursera: IBM Data Science Professional

- Open-Source Tools for DS
- DS Methodology
- Python for DS and AI
- Databases and SQL for DS
- Data Analysis & Visualization with Python
- Machine Learning with Python
- Applied DS Capstone

IBM Skill Badges

- "Be Equal" Ambassador
- Cognitive Practitioner Badge
- Disruptive HR in a Cognitive Era
- Emotional Intelligence I
- Earning Client Advocacy
- Agile Explorer

University of Piraeus e-Learning

Basic Business Functions on SAP ERP

GMAT

- Total: 640 (68th percentile)
- Integrated Reasoning: 8 (92nd percentile)
- Analytical Writing Assessment: 6 (88th percentile)

IT SKILLS

- MS Office (Access, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, Outlook)
- IBM SPSS, STATA, Tableau, PowerBI
- SQL (Excel, QMF, Jupyter, SQL Server)

- Python & R (Anaconda, Jupyter, RStudio, Watson)
- SAP ERP (FI/CO, MM, SD, WM), Fiken
- Adobe Visuals (Lightroom, PremierePro, Photoshop)

AWARDS

- Outstanding Achievement Award University of Cologne
- Graduation Excellence Scholarship
 "Phaedon Hadjigeorgiou" Foundation
- Erasmus+ Student Excellence Scholarship
 Athens University of Economics & Business
- Bronze Award for Online Photography
 National & Kapodistrian University of Athens

VOLUNTEERING

10.2017 - 09.2021 **The Balkans**, Peacebuilding & Environmental activism 07.2019 - 07.2020 **Спаси София! (Save Sofia!)**, Filming & Video Editing

10.2015 - 05.2016 Athens Sunday School of Migrants & Refugees, Teaching of Greek to migrants/refugees

08.2014 - 08.2015 Animal Welfare Association of Nea Filadelfeia, Stray animal rescue

CAUSES I CARE ABOUT & INTERESTS

Animal welfare & environment

Civil rights & poverty alleviationDiversity & social inclusion

Traveling

Floristry

Hiking

Psychology

Digital & drone photography

Vegan cuisine